## Clayton W. Seitz, Ph.D.

## cwseitz@iu.edu cwseitz.github.io

# PERSONAL STATEMENT

I have a demonstrated ability to advance multi-disciplinary team projects at the interface of biology and quantitative sciences. My experience includes the integration of deep neural networks and large language models with genetic/omic datasets. I can train, test, and maintain state of the art models for predictions while maintaining best practices in AI/ML.

## **EDUCATION**

# Doctor of Philosopy, Physics

2024

Purdue University

#### Master of Science, Physics

2021

University of Chicago

#### Bachelor of Science, Physics, Magna Cum Laude

2019

Indiana University
Minor: Mathematics

# Bachelor of Science, Informatics (Math Focus), Magna Cum Laude

2019

Indiana University

#### **EXPERIENCE**

#### Graduate Researcher

2021-2024

Purdue University, Indianapolis, IN

- Designed, developed, and deployed deep neural network models on biologically oriented datasets
- Analyzed high-dimensional molecular data, including transcriptomics and imaging/video datasets
- Explored the application of generative AI to enhance workflows and provide new insights
- Applied predictive models to research and publish findings on autoimmune diseases such as type-1 diabetes
- Used advanced data visualization and communication techniques to give engaging presentations of results

#### Graduate Researcher

2020-2021

University of Chicago, Chicago, IL

- Investigated fundamental learning mechanisms in recurrent neural networks (RNNs) using dynamical models, mean-field theory, and time-series analysis.
- Designed and ran Monte Carlo simulations of spiking neural networks

## Research Assistant

2018-2020

Purdue University, Indianapolis, IN

- Developed a scientific package in Python for high-throughput object detection and tracking
- Managed the package lifecycle and user training throughout the laboratory

AWARDS

NIH Graduate Training Fellowship University of Chicago, Chicago, IL

2020

Travel Award and Lightning Talk Invitation Physical Sciences in Oncology - Minneapolis, MN 2019

Hudson and Holland Scholarship for Diversity and Inclusion

2013-2017

Indiana University, Bloomington, IN

Founders Scholar

2013-2017

Indiana University, Bloomington, IN

Cigital Scholarship

2016-2017

Indiana University, Bloomington, IN

PUBLICATIONS Clayton Seitz<sup>†</sup>, Donghong Fu<sup>†</sup>, Mengyuan Liu, Hailan Ma, and Jing Liu. BRD4 phosphorylation regulates the structure of chromatin nanodomains. Physical Review Letters (In Review). https://doi.org/10.1101/2024.09.03.611057. 2024

> Clayton Seitz and Jing Liu. Uncertainty-aware localization microscopy by variational diffusion. In Review. 2024

> Clayton Seitz and Jing Liu. Quantum enhanced localization microscopy with a single photon avalanche diode array. In Review. 2024

> Maelle Locatelli<sup>†</sup>, Josh Lawrimore<sup>†</sup>, Hua Lin<sup>†</sup>, Sarvath Sanaullah, Clayton Seitz, Dave Segall, Paul Kefer, Salvador Moreno Naike, Benton Lietz, Rebecca Anderson, Julia Holmes, Chongli Yuan, George Holzwarth, Bloom Kerry, Jing Liu, Keith D Bonin, Pierre-Alexandre Vidi. DNA damage reduces heterogeneity and coherence of chromatin motions. PNAS 12 July 2022; 119 (29): 1-11

> Mengdi Zhang, Clayton Seitz, Garrick Chang, Fadil Iqbal, Hua Lin, and Jing Liu A guide for single-particle chromatin tracking in live cell nuclei. Cell Biology International 15 January 2022; 46 (5): 683-700

> Wenting Wu, Farooq Syed, Edward Simpson, Chih-Chun Lee, Jing Liu, Garrick Chang, Chuanpeng Dong, Clayton Seitz, Decio L. Eizirik, Raghavendra G. Mirmira, Yunlong Liu, Carmella Evans-Molina; Impact of Proinflammatory Cytokines on Alternative Splicing Patterns in Human Islets. Diabetes 25 October 2021; 71 (1): 116 - 127

> Clayton Seitz, Hailan Ma, and Jing Liu. Cytokine-induced transcriptional memory is evident in the kinetics of transcriptional bursts. Biophysical Society Annual Conference 2022

> Clayton Seitz, Hua Lin, Keith Bonin, Pierre-Alexandre Vidi, and Jing Liu. Quantifying the spatiotemporal dynamics of dUTP labeled chromatin during the DNA damage response. Biophysical Society Annual Conference 2020

**SOFTWARE SKILLS** 

Programming Languages & Software: Linux, Bash, Python, R, PyTorch, C/C++, SQL, LaTeX, Git, Docker, SLURM, AWS